Guide to the Carlos "DJ Styles" Garza Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Carlos "DJ Styles" Garza Papers
1985-2011
06/2013-009
Carlos "DJ Styles" Garza
2.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection includes personal records, fliers, posters, photographs, business records, audiocassettes, and memorabilia belonging to Carlos “DJ Styles” Garza, and relating to his work as a b-boy, DJ, and hip-hop music producer in Houston from the mid-1980s to 2011.
Biographical Information:
Carlos Garza was born in Mexico and moved to Houston with his family in the 1970s. As a teenager in Bellaire, he fell in love with hip hop music and culture. In the mid-1980s Carlos began break dancing under the name DJ Pace Master. He and a few friends formed the Dynamic Crew, a break dancing group which performed at parties and participated in contests. After a year of break dancing, he decided to switch to DJing and began performing under the name DJ Styles. In 1986, Carlos began working at Soundwaves and, due to his love of the genre, was put in charge of ordering all of the hip hop music. This role allowed him to develop relationships with major hip hop record labels, which came in handy when he started working as a hip hop music producer. Garza has worked as a producer for hip hop artists such as the Odd Squad, Devin the Dude, and the Coughee Brothaz, and continues producing, mixing, and mastering hip hop music to this day.
Sources:
Faniel, Maco L. “Hip-Hop in Houston: The Origin and the Legacy.” The History Press. 2013
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Odd Squad (Musical group)
Genre/Form of Material:
Business records; Drawings (visual works); Fliers (printed matter); Memorabilia
Personal Name:
Devin the Dude, 1969-; Garza, Carlos "DJ Styles"
Topical Term:
Disc jockeys -- Texas -- Houston; Hip-hop -- Texas -- Houston; Rap (Music) -- Texas -- Houston; Rap musicians -- Texas -- Houston
Accruals:
Additional materials were donated by Carlos Garza on 02/24/2014
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Related Materials:
Carols (DJ Styles) Garza Drawings and Memorabilia digital collection (http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/2013_009)
Scope and Contents
This collection includes personal records, fliers, posters, photographs, business records, audiocassettes, and memorabilia belonging to Carlos “DJ Styles” Garza, and relating to his work as a b-boy, DJ, and hip-hop music producer in Houston from the mid-1980s to 2011. This collection is divided into six series: Personal Papers, Business Records, Promotional Materials, Publications, Memorabilia, and Audiocassettes. Items within each series are arranged chronologically wherever dates are available.
Detailed List of Contents
- Personal Papers
  - Dates and Addresses
    - Datebook, February 1986-March 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Datebook, August 2004-December 2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Address Book, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Contacts List, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Drawings and Artwork
    Scope and Contents
    This sub-series contains drawings by Carlos Garza and by two of his friends, Frosty Ice and Gino.
    - Carlos Garza Drawings, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Drawings by Gino, approximately 1986 – 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Artwork by Frosty Ice, 1988 (Ovs box 1, Folder 1)
  - Personal Photos
    - Personal photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Personal photos, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 2)
  - Operation Brightside Summer Youth Employment Program
    This sub-series contains records relating to the Operation Brightside Summer Youth Employment Program, which was a program co-sponsored by the Houston Area Urban League and Anheuser-Busch Inc.
    - Operation Brightside News, August 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Business Records
  This series contains business records relating to Carlos Garza’s work as a hip hop music producer for performers like the Odd Squad, Devin the Dude, and the Coughee Brothaz.
  - Odd Squad, approximately 1993 – 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Royalty Statements, 1994 – 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Checks, 1993 – 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Receipts, December 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Harry Fox Agency Info Packet, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Certificate to operate under the name “The Craft”, February 2003 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Promotional Materials
  - Fliers
    This sub-series contains fliers collected by Carlos Garza. The first folder holds fliers specifically for Garza’s breakdancing group, the Dynamic Crew, while the second folder holds fliers for various musical artists.
    - Dynamic Crew Fliers, approximately 1986 – 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Fliers – Various Artists, approximately 1987 – 1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Promotional Photographs
    - Promotional Photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Promotional folders
    - The Odd Squad, approximately 1990 – 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Camillion, approximately 2003 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Mike B., 2005 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Odd Squad Poster, undated (Drawer F.3, Ovs folder 7)
  - Promo Cards
    - Various Hip Hop Artists, approximately 2005 – 2011 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Posters and Poster Flats
    - Devin the Dude Poster Flat and Sticker, 1998 (Ovs box 1, Folder 3)
    - Coughee Brothaz Poster, April 2011 (Ovs box 1, Folder 4)
- Publications
  - Billboard Charts, July 1992, March 1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Hip Hop Magazines, 1994 – 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Assault Guns Most Often Used in Crimes Handout, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Billboard Charts, February 1995 – March 1994 (Ovs box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Articles, September 1993, March 1994 (Ovs box 1, Folder 6)
- Memorabilia
  - Business Cards from Book 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Business Cards from Book 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Business Cards from Binder, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Pins and buttons, undated (Ovs box 2, Item 1)
  - Four African medallions sold at Soundwaves, undated (Ovs box 3, Item 1)
  - Two stacks of ticket stubs from various movies, concerts, and events, approximately 1987 – 2009 (Ovs box 3, Item 2)
  - Two AstroWorld name tags, undated (Ovs box 3, Item 3)
  - Two armbands from concerts, 1992, 1995 (Ovs box 3, Item 4)
  - Blacksheep Skins Condom, undated (Ovs box 3, Item 5)
  - Two keychains, undated (Ovs box 3, Item 6)
  - Yellow hair pick, undated (Ovs box 4, Item 1)
  - Stack of badges from concerts and events, approximately 1989 – 2005 (Ovs box 4, Item 2)
  - Fossil watch sleeve and receipt, undated (Ovs box 4, Item 3)
- Audiocassettes
  This series contains fifteen audiocassettes collected by Carlos Garza. They are arranged alphabetically by artist within the box.
  - Audiocassettes, approximately 1988 – 1999 (Box 2, Item 1)